# Krish Shah

krish.shah2903@gmail.com

+44 7405 794655

linkedin.com/in/krish-shah004

github.com/krish2903

I am an avid programmer on the course for a First-Class Honours Degree in BSc Computer Science with Management (ITMB) at the Queen Mary University of London. I am highly motivated to learn new programming languages and frameworks within software and web development. Possessing a multilingual ability, with fluency in Hindi, Chinese and English, it makes me a strong communicator with culturally distinct individuals. I visualise myself as a strong marketer, focused manager and an adept software developer within 5 years.

## Education

#### Taipei European School

Aug 2018 - Sep 2022

- IGCSEs: Mathematics (A\*), Computer Science (A\*), ICT (A\*), Economics (A), English (A), Chinese (A\*).
- IB (Total 43/45 points): Mathematics (7), Computer Science (7), Business Management (7) at Higher Level.

## Queen Mary University of London

Sep 2022 - Present

- Bachelor's Of Science (BSc) in Computer Science with Management (ITMB): Predicted 1:1
- Coursework: Procedural Programming | OOP | Computer Systems & Networks | Web Technology | Database Systems | Software Engineering | Project Risk Management | Information Systems | Economics | Financial Accounting | Business Modelling | Marketing.

## Work Experience

#### OOP Demonstrator | Queen Mary University of London | London, UK

Jan 2023 - Jun 2023

- Responsible for marking OOP coding exercises, quizzes and a final horse race GUI project.
- Explained OOP concepts of abstraction, encapsulation, polymorphism and inheritance to students.

## Technology Consultant | Aniraj Exports | Mumbai, India

Jun 2022 - Oct 2022

- Developed and implemented a data scraping algorithm using python to extract and format raw sales data from the Kohinoor accounting software to a processed csv file, improving data handling and readability.
- Processed raw data to produce graphs using matplotlib and pandas, creating break-even analysis charts for risk management.
- Gained more insight into diamond, jewellery and the import/export industry.

## Top Projects

#### Employee Timesheet Portal | FDM Group | React JS | Python Flask | MySQL | APIs

Feb 2023 - May 2024

- Developed a full-stack timesheets website, with a team, for FDM consultants to track & manage salary payments.
- · Led and managed the front-end team, ideating and developing designs as per client requirements, with high usability and accessibility.
- Achieved the best prototype presentation out of 50+ groups.

### Accounting & Stock Management System | Aniraj Exports | Python (PyQt)

Aug 2021 - Apr 2022

- Developed a custom GUI using PyQt & QtDesigner for the accounting interface, increasing transaction input accuracy by up to 90%.
- Implemented web scraping using the python bs4 library to accumulate exchange rates from Xe for accurate currency conversion.
- Improved data handling and storage by formatting product details into csv files, to be accessed directly from the GUI.

## Certifications

#### Software Engineering Virtual Experience Program | Goldman Sachs

Sep 2024

- Completed a job simulation as a Goldman Sachs governance analyst responsible for assessing IT security and suggesting improvements.
- Identified that the company was using an outdated MD5 password hashing algorithm by cracking passwords using Hashcat.
- Wrote a memo for my supervisor summarizing a range of proposed uplifts to increase the company's level of password protection including changes in their password policy, password salting, key stretching, MFA, and using the bcrypt hashing algorithm.

#### Web Development Job Simulation | Moreton Bay Regional Council Entrepreneurship & Innovation

Sep 2023

- Completed a job simulation involving website planning and creation.
- Created a sitemap and userflow using a diagram creation tool, thereby creating a simple landing page frontend using HTML/CSS.

## Skills

Programming Skills / IDEs: Python | Java | HTML | CSS | React JS | PHP | Django | SQL | VSCode | IntelliJ | GitHub | Visual Paradigm Other Technical Skills: Microsoft Products (*PowerPoint, Excel, Word, Outlook, Teams*) | Google Products (*Slides, Sheets, Docs, Forms, Mail*)

Soft Skills: Multilingual (Chinese, Hindi, English fluency) | Problem-solving | Time Management | Organisation | Teamwork | Critical Thinking